<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Dr. D - Research</title><link href="https://dschreij.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://dschreij.github.io/feeds/research.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://dschreij.github.io/</id><updated>2017-02-07T08:39:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>What do people look at when they view a painting?</title><link href="https://dschreij.github.io/research/van-gogh-eyetracking-project" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-07T08:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T08:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Schreij</name></author><id>tag:dschreij.github.io,2017-02-07:/research/van-gogh-eyetracking-project</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was part of this ambitious project in which we used a mobile eye tracker to study what people look at in various van Gogh paintings.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you view a particular scene or painting, what areas or objects do you look at? Does everyone look at a painting in a different way, or is there some generic pattern or strategy that most of us follow? These questions have often been explored in perception science or cognitive psychology. Most studies into this topic presented images of paintings to participants on a computer screen, while their gaze was tracked with stationary and often bulky eye trackers. These require participants to sit down and keep their head extremely still (and lay it on a chin rest), because the slightest head movement can throw off the tracker's calibration. And of course, these types of studies need to take place in a lab, because the eye trackers are not easy to carry around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not really what one would call a natural setting to study viewing behavior in. Normally we have the ability to walk around, and often we also turn our heads in the direction of the things we want to look at. Luckily, light-weight mobile eye trackers have started to hit the market in the last few years and they allow researchers to study participants in less restricted settings. Most of these mobile eye trackers are really expensive (think of $50,000+), but lately some vendors have started to offer options that are quite affordable. One that particularly caught our attention was the &lt;a href="https://pupil-labs.com/pupil/"&gt;Pupil mobile eyetracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot" class="center-block half-width" src="https://dschreij.github.io/images/blog/pupil_eyetracker.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its development started out as a project for a Master's thesis in Berlin to see if it was possible to create a cheap mobile eye tracker with components extracted from webcams, and led to the establishment of a company: &lt;a href="https://pupil-labs.com/"&gt;Pupil Labs&lt;/a&gt;. This little device can be purchased for between $1,500 and $2,500 and only weighs around 50 grams. It plugs into a laptop with two usb cables (one for the eye camera and one for the camera filming in the direction the wearer is looking at; the more expensive models have both integrated into one usb-connector). The recording software is open-source, well maintained (although it can be a bit buggy because new features and other improvements are constantly added) and free to download. The only downside is that there currently is no officially supported software package that helps with quantitative analysis of the recorded data, but probably that is on the company's roadmap somewhere (In the meantime, I wrote &lt;a href="https://github.com/dschreij/PupilEyetrackerAnalysisTools"&gt;a small library of my own for this purpose&lt;/a&gt;, but haven't maintained it really well). Pupil does however supply software that allows one to visually inspect the recorded data, &lt;a href="https://github.com/pupil-labs/pupil/wiki/Pupil-Player"&gt;Pupil Player&lt;/a&gt;, which is great (it borders on sci-fi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the pupil eyetracker in our possession at the &lt;a href="http://www.vupsy.nl"&gt;Cognitive Psychology department&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Vrije&lt;/em&gt; Universiteit of Amsterdam, &lt;a href="https://www.utwente.nl/en/et/vvr/staff/walker/"&gt;Francesco Walker&lt;/a&gt; came up with a nice idea to use it for a research project. Besides his interest in human perception, he also likes art. Why not combine the two? His suggestion was to use the Pupil to study how people appreciate visual art, or more specifically, look at paintings. He contacted various museums in Amsterdam to propose this project, but only the &lt;a href="https://www.vangoghmuseum.nl/en"&gt;Van Gogh Museum&lt;/a&gt; (seriously, if you ever visit Amsterdam, don't skip it!) responded and was enthusiastic about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So off we went. With our team consisting of Francesco, &lt;a href="http://www.vupsy.nl/staff-members/berno-bucker/"&gt;Berno Bucker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.vupsy.nl/staff-members/nicola-c-anderson/"&gt;Nicola Andersson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.vupsy.nl/staff-members/jan-theeuwes/"&gt;Prof. Jan Theeuwes&lt;/a&gt; and me, we studied how people's gaze travels through 5 different Van Gogh paintings during two separate phases. The first time, participants were asked to just view the paintings as they would during a normal museum visit. They had 30 seconds to look at each painting, after which they were led to the next painting, untill they had seen all five. After this first phase, they were told more about the background of each painting and Van Gogh's reasons for painting it. Being more informed, they were requested to view each painting again for the same amount of time. We furthermore compared if there was a difference in viewing behavior between adults and children that were finishing elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, we found a difference. In the first phase, the viewing behavior of the children was driven more by properties of the scene, while the adults showed viewing behavior was more goal-driven (they tried to view with a purpose, while the children just looked at areas in the painting that were more salient). In the second phase, the viewing behaviors converged; both groups were looked at the paintings in a more goal-driven fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a demo video of the study that also shows the abilities of the Pupil Player quite nicely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9"&gt;
&lt;iframe class="embed-responsive-item" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0_KaItdTkEM?rel=0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For those who'd like to know more: a paper about this study has been submitted and is currently under review. Once (if...) it gets published, I will try to link it here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Perception"></category><category term="Science"></category><category term="Eye tracking"></category><category term="Art"></category></entry></feed>